

# CONTACT ME AT

- Home Address: 19 Chiene St., Uwani, Enugu state, Nigeria 400251
- marycynthiamarachi@gmail.com
- +234 906 339 9674
- in <u>@amarachi-ugwu</u>
- @Marycynthia-mara

#### PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- •••• PHP
- •••• Node JS
- ••• React JS
- •••• JQuery
- •••• MySQL
- ••• Bootstrap
- •••• CSS
- •••• HTML
- •••• Express
- •••• Vanilla Javascript
- •••• AJAX

# **AMARACHI UGWU**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a full stack Web developer with 3+ years of experience in the development, usage and implementation of data driven web applications. I have knowledge of languages and technologies such as PHP, JavaScript, Node JS, React, MySQL, HTML, CSS, J Query, AJAX, Express, Bootstrap etc.

I am enthusiastic about software development, community development and also am a fast learner and harness my ability to quickly share, master and apply new knowledge.

#### MY OBJECTIVE

My objective is to secure a challenging position where my skills and experiences will be fully utilized to speed up and contribute tremendously to the growth of the organization, community and teams I work with, and to add more values to myself, people around me and the whole world at large.

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Software Engineer

Geneus Interactive Technologies | April 2019 - present

 Worked on several projects with my team such as development of personal/organisation websites, ecommerce websites, brand websites, management systems and many more.

# Programming/Basic Computer Training Instructor

C-TECH International LTD |Oct 2017 – Aug 2018

- Taught my students how to use the computer, starting from how to boot a computer to relationships, connections and uses of the computer and its peripherals.
- I also taught them how to work with basic programs such as Microsoft offices, paint, CorelDraw and more.
- For student who have the above knowledge I go further to educate them on more advanced courses like HTML and CSS.

#### **DESIGN SKILLS**

- ••• Figma
- ••• Canva
- • • Photoshop
- •••• CorelDraw

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- •••• Back-end Development
- ••• UI/UX Designing
- ••• Front-end Development
- •••• Graphic Design

#### COMPETENCES

teamwork, leadership, open mindedness, transparency, like mindedness, patience, hardworking, consistency, working without supervision and honesty.

# INTERESTS

Software development, blockchain, smart contracts, Artificial intelligence, Data Science, Robotics Community development, Network Marketing, Digital Marketing.

#### INTERNSHIPS

- CODE LARNABLE20 organised by Genesys Tech Hub (2020) Enugu Nigeria
- Pink Summer of Code organised by Tenece (2019) Enugu Nigeria

#### **AFFLIATIONS**

- Member Google Developers
  Group
- Member Women Tech Makers
- Member She Code Africa

#### EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

# National Open University Of Nigeria

Bachelor Of Computer Science (B.Sc.) | (Jan 2019 - Till Date

- President, Computer and Technology Organization
- Vice President, Programming Club
- Member, NOUN developers group
- Member, Student IT Forum

# **Aptech Computer Education**

Web Development with PHP (Diploma) | Aug 2018 - Feb 2019.

- Sr No.: 01663.
- Best Graduating student of the year

#### ACCOMPLISHMENTS

# School Management System and website

Github link to the management system, click here.

- Manages Events for the school: post events details with pictures, update, delete of event(s).
- Newsletter subscription.
- Manages students' data: assign classes, generate results
- Manages Admission: process student admission into the school.
- Manages staff's data. assign staff duty, assign staff class.

# Business Management System and website

Github Link to the management system, click here.

- Manages Projects and products for the business.: post products/projects details with pictures, update, delete of products/projects(s).
- Newsletter subscription.
- Generate invoice, proposals and document projects.
- Manage business finance amd marketing.

### **BOOKS READ**

- Eloquent JavaScript a modern introduction to programming (by Marijn Haverbeke).
- Head First JavaScript Programming (by Eric Freeman and Elisabeth Robson).
- HTML& CSS: Design and Build website (by Jon Duckket).
   And more